[HANGE] I never expected Floch
to take action this quickly.
[MAGATH] If the Jaegerists
destroy the flying boat,
our plan would be
dead in the water.
So why haven't they
done it already?
[HANGE]
Hard to say.
If I had to guess,
they suspect we're alive,
and maybe that we're
trying to stop Eren,
but they're not entirely sure.
They could blow it up
in a second if they wanted to,
but they can't
build another one.
Without the
Azumabito's knowledge,
they would have to
start from scratch.
They'll wanna use it
for themselves if they can,
to make sure the mainland's
been wiped clean.
Plus, there're Azumabito
ships here.
That might be
their real objective:
to capture a small fleet
and the technicians
to keep it afloat.
But regardless.
The Jaegerists would readily
sacrifice that objective
if they caught wind of us.
They'll blow the flying boat to
bits the second we're spotted.
We've got a few of the Nine,
so our odds are
better than they'd be
in a straight firefight.
But not good.
[MAGATH] True. We'll just
have to make the best of it.
Fighting the Founder'll
be even worse.
[Gasps]
We'd better plan to--
♪ Opening Song ♪
[ANNIE] We have no choice
but to kill 'em all
with our first strike.
That's the only way we can
secure the flying boat.
To pull this off,
everyone's gotta be in sync.
We need our Titan power and
your firepower. Understood?
Just hold on a second.
What's the problem?
The Jaegerists are holding
all the Azumabito hostage.
We need to keep them
out of the line of fire.
[CONNY gasps]
Yeah, exactly!
You expect us to
care about that?
We won't protect people
who've attacked our homeland
just 'cause they're
your distant cousins.
[PIECK] Slow down, Annie.
If the hostages are killed,
the rest of the plan
falls apart.
Right, Onyankopon?
Yeah, we need him alive.
I should be able to
pilot their boat,
but first we gotta
get it into flying shape.
That's the problem.
We need the mechanics
to set up the wings.
Otherwise, none of us are
gonna be flying anywhere.
The wings are folded up
to make it easier to tow,
so they'll need to be
extended and secured.
And even then,
there's still more to do
before we can get airborne.
[ONYANKOPON] The original
plan was to hangar it
'til we had some pilots trained,
so we're skipping
a lot of steps,
but they'll at least
need some time
to service it before takeoff.
Start to finish, how long
is it gonna take to service?
I couldn't say.
It'll be up to the mechanics.
I get it. But to confirm,
you're asking us to protect
the Azumabito technicians
from the Jaegerists long enough
to get the boat ready to fly.
And let me guess.
You want us to
hold the enemy off
for this unknown length of time
without killing any of them.
If at all possible.
We've known these guys
ever since we were cadets.
Then I'm sure you've got a plan.
Think you could fill me in?
We don't even have
an estimate on
how long the Azumabito
will need yet.
So you must have some scheme to
keep the Jaegerists
occupied indefinitely
without killing them.
Can you explain it in detail?
There is a plan, right, Armin?
You had one for me.
There's no way
to make that happen.
We have to wipe them out
with a lightning strike,
or else a survivor will destroy
the boat and strand us here.
[CONNY] Hold on! We can see
that it's a long shot,
but we're doing this
to help people!
So what? You're saying
we have to gun down
a bunch of our friends
to save the world?
That's so messed up!
[ANNIE] I'm sorry. This'll be
a pretty ugly operation.
We shouldn't expect
you guys to take part in it.
We don't even have the right
to drop that choice on you.
If it had been you in our place,
you probably would have
chosen differently
than we did that day.
You wouldn't have
breached the wall.
[Gasps]
Turns out that I was right.
I am the same as you.
[REINER]
Is that what he was saying?
[REINER] None of you
need to join this battle.
[REINER]
Stick with Gabi and Falco.
Stay at a safe distance
and observe.
You'll have to defend yourselves
if the Jaegerists spot you,
so be prepared to fight.
But for now,
just stay out of it.
And let you guys kill each other
while we sit back and watch?
Would that work?
Can Titans even win this
without infantry
backing them up?
[Gasps]
[HANGE] I've got no intention
of being a spectator.
Look. I know they
were our comrades,
but I've already
had to shoot four.
On top of that, our window
for saving humanity
is shorter than we realized.
I saw the Titans
crossing the sea,
leaving monstrous clouds
of steam in their wake,
and considering how fast
they were moving,
they've probably made
landfall in Marley by now.
The closest cities in
Northeastern Marley
are most likely gone.
I had no idea
they would be able to
make it across
the sea that quickly.
There's no telling how many
people they've already killed.
Tell us where Eren Jaeger
is going with those Titans!
[MAGATH grunting]
Every time you make me
ask you again,
I'll break you a new elbow!
[MAGATH grunts]
[YELENA screams]
[HANGE]
Magath, stop it!
[gasps]
Why do you look so damn afraid?
I'm not gonna kill you.
That's certainly good to hear.
I've changed my mind.
Now that you've
caught me up in this,
I don't wanna die without
knowing how it ends.
If we survive,
and you take me with you,
I might tell you
where to find Eren.
Securing that boat
is priority one.
Yeah. Torturing her isn't
gonna do us any good now.
Forgive me. All of you.
I was a fool.
I'm sorry for
my behavior last night.
We were never in the right.
I'd deluded myself into thinking
we were the good guys.
I wanted to believe
the evil I'd done
was justified as part of
some great cause.
But in the end,
that's just not true.
I'd attempted to
ignore the fact that
Marley's soul has grown rotten,
as I didn't want to consider
what that said about me.
This war isn't your fault.
You shouldn't be punished
for the sins of people
you never knew simply because
their blood flows in your veins.
[MAGATH]
Pieck. Annie. Reiner.
You've been shouldering the
burden of humanity's hatred
since you were born.
It's inexcusable.
But still.
Senseless as our
bloodstained history may be,
we have a duty to pass it on,
so the generations
after us can do better.
Jaeger plans to
erase everything,
including the lessons
of the past.
And I call that unforgivable.
As long as this wanton
killing continues,
our world will only
sink deeper into hell.
We have to break the cycle!
[BOTH gasp]
But right now,
we're trapped in it.
There's no way to avoid
spilling more blood today.
So please, look the other way.
[ARMIN]
I'm not doing that.
I refuse to let someone else
stain their hands in my place.
[FLOCH] Look at the size
of those steam clouds.
History has never changed
so much in a single day!
[FLOCH] Of course, the history
of Hizuru will change as well.
All of civilization is
about to be flattened,
and something new
will arise where it stood.
Whatever concerns you had
will soon be dead and gone.
We have only the future
to worry about,
so focus on what you can
contribute to the island.
These gentlemen, for instance.
Hizuru's brightest
engineers will be
a valuable asset to
our homeland. Right?
It would be a shame to
have to lose any more of them,
so please kindly
do as you're told.
I was hoping I could
avoid saying anything
that would disrupt
this fine mood you're in.
Huh?
But what is this change
you speak of,
and what good do you
think would come of it?
If you believe slaughtering
the human race
will guarantee peace
here on Paradis,
you'll be quite disappointed.
You won't make your world
any less violent
by making it smaller.
When tomorrow comes,
you'll have accomplished
nothing more than containing
the killing to your own home.
I'll take your words to heart.
In fact, I've been approaching
the same conclusion.
But in any world, it's important
to understand our place.
Hizuru's technology
would be useful to Eldia,
but our security's
our greatest concern,
and we don't need a flying boat
or a seafaring fleet to
move forward as a nation.
Trouble will be
nipped in the bud. Got it?
This is the world now.
You need to recognize your place
in it. Do you understand?
[ARMIN]
Floch! Where are you?
We need the Azumabito!
Wait, Armin?
[ARMIN]
There you are!
[FLOCH]
What are you yelling for?
Where have you been?
[ARMIN]
I was following the Cart Titan!
It regrouped with
the Armored Titan.
They're escaping
together by sea!
We can't let them
catch up with Eren!
We need that
flying boat airborne!
Tell the Azumabito mechanics
to get it ready, right now!
What are you telling me, Armin?
Why didn't you
chase after the Cart?
If you had,
this would be over by now!
It was obvious that
they were gonna head south!
Now we've lost them.
You know they killed Jean
and Onyonkopon, right?
[CONNY] Armin!
The flying boat's over here!
[ARMIN] Floch! Get the
Azumabito mechanics
down here right away!
--Hold on!
--Stop right there!
[CONNY] Daz? Samuel?
What are you doing?
[CONNY gasps]
Are those explosives?
[ARMIN]
Get 'em off the boat already!
[CONNY] Hurry up, we gotta
get this thing ready to launch!
The Marleyans are
gonna get away!
--[DAZ] Easy!
--[SAMUEL] Settle down, okay?
We need to talk first.
There have been rumors
going around since yesterday.
People say you guys
teamed up with Marley,
and that you plan to
use the flying boat
to stop the rumbling.
That's not true, is it?
[ARMIN gasps]
What? What kinda
crazy talk is that?
We're with you!
Eren has to finish the job,
or this island is doomed!
Yeah. That's what I thought.
We've been fighting so long
to save our home.
After all you've been through,
I knew there was no way you'd
put us in danger again.
Yeah, you're damn right,
there's not!
That's a relief.
If you'd actually
turned your backs on us,
I can't even imagine
what I would have done.
[ARMIN] But we didn't, Daz.
Now, the explosives, please?
[DAZ]
I know you get that Eren's doing
what's necessary to protect us.
But a part of me still
thought you might
side with the enemy
and try to stop him.
[Gasps] What's wrong, guys?
I disconnected the detonator.
[ARMIN]
That's done.
Now we have to hope
Floch listens to me
and sends out the
Azumabito mechanics.
[ARMIN]
If we can get the boat ready,
all we'll need is a way to get
our team aboard, and it's over.
There's a chance
we can pull this off
and stop Eren without
any more killing.
[FLOCH]
Think about it.
It doesn't quite
add up, does it?
Armin said it was obvious that
the enemy would
flee to the south,
but the locomotive is
the fastest way here.
[FLOCH] Instead,
they pursued on horseback,
even though the Cart
already had a head start.
[sighs] What have
they been up to
since they went incommunicado?
Truth is, there's no
proof of anything.
Still, my gut tells me
this is trouble.
So it's time to nip some buds.
[ALL gasp]
[Gunshots]
[ARMIN]
We failed!
--[JAEGERIST 85A] Hey!
--[JAEGERIST 85B] Floch!
Idiots! Quit staring
and blow her away!
Did you think I'd
go down without a fight?
[MIKASA grunts]
Kiyomi, run!
[Yells]
We're under attack!
Mikasa, Armin, and Conny
have switched sides!
They've betrayed
Eldia! Kill them!
[MIKASA gasps] They're gonna
fire through the windows!
Get down to the basement!
[Gasps]
[MIKASA]
It's a firefight now.
The only way through
is to wipe out
every last Jaegerist!
[KIYOMI]
Lady Mikasa!
[MIKASA yells]
[MAGATH]
This way, all of you!
We can hunker down
in the basement!
If you wanna stay alive,
then come with me!
Hold on!
Wait, Daz! What are
you trying to--
--Armin!
--[SAMUEL] Don't move!
[CONNY]
Samuel.
Don't stop.
Reconnect the detonator
and blow up the boat.
Hurry up, Daz!
[CONNY]
Samuel? Hey.
[SAMUEL] You said we'd
eat meat together, Conny.
And we finally could've
made that happen.
We've got room
to raise livestock,
just like we imagined it!
[SAMUEL] Dammit all to hell.
How did it end up like this?
The only way out of here
is through the enemy!
We'll be overrun
as soon as they regroup!
We'll be fine!
As long as we're down here,
we'll be safe when
our reinforcements
jump into the fray
up on the surface!
Enemy in the basement!
Follow me and
bring more explosives!
[FLOCH] Why would they
back themselves into a corner?
[FLOCH]
No. They didn't!
[Gasps]
[CONNY yells]
[ONYANKOPON] The plan failed.
Why does it always end this way?
Violence will always be
a part of human existence,
won't it, Captain?
[JAEGERISTS gasp]
[JAEGERISTS scream]
[JAEGERIST 85O] We need to
get more Thunder Spears!
No, no, no!
You have to blow up
the boat, Daz!
[Gasps]
Stop, Armin!
Get off me!
[DAZ]
I don't wanna do this!
Armin!
Why are you betraying us?
I don't understand, Conny!
We were supposed to be on
the same side, no matter what!
We still are on
the same side, Samuel!
But I-- I just--!
One of you is gonna have to
be the one to do it.
[CONNY yelling]
Wait, Conny--
[BERTHOLDT] One of you has to
stain your hands with my blood!
[CONNY screams]
♪ Ending Song ♪
[NARRATOR]
Hesitation is death.
Aim the gun and
pull the trigger,
and know that
with your betrayal,
the world might live
to see another day.
Next episode: "Retrospective."